Stephen Kent

Backend Software Developer

- ♀ 2700 Dorr Ave, VA 22031, Fairfax (US)
- stevekcode@gmail.com
- (571) 295-6530
- n stevejkcode in linkedin html pdf

About

I'm a backend web developer with several years of experience developing, maintaining, and managing cloud native web applications. In addition to implementation I have been responsible for driving the full development lifecycle, from design through to deployment, maintenance and operations and I am comfortable handling the demands of modern software projects. In my spare time I'm usually playing guitar (badly) or learning French.

Experience

Capital One

March 2016 - July 2022

Mid Backend Developer

Developed Cyber Security solutions to enable developers to build secure software early in the development lifecycle. Principle engineer and architect on a platform to orchestrate and automate static and open source scanners for teams across the enterprise while also improving reporting and finding quality.

- Instrumental in the design of a software project that helped make it easier for developers across the company to write secure code.
- Worked to design and deploy cloud native software on AWS
- Drove database and schema designs in Mongo & Dynamo with some minor experience in PostgreSQL.
- Designed and implemented solutions for distributed work systems using SQS and Bull, which is an open source job queue framework that uses Redis.
- Reviewed and helped mentor the work of more junior team members through PRs and informal pair programming sessions.
- Co-author of US Patent No. 10,387,659 for the de-duplication of static source code security findings.
- Developed disaster recovery plans and carried them out successfully during internal exercises.

CFPB

November 2014 - December 2015

Jr. Backend Developer

Backend software developer working on tools to facilitate consumer protections and regulatory oversight. Developed a linting tool to help improve data quality for regulator submissions via a rules engine with rules defined in a flexible JSON schema.

- Created a business rule engine which uses flexible JSON specifications.
- Wrote unit tests for all code I developed using mocha.js and must.js.
- Developed a REST API for querying against public data (Census, etc) using kraken.js.
- Used MongoDB for persistence along with Mongoose as an ODM.

FCC

March 2014 - November 2014

Jr. Backend Developer

Developed backend Python code for aggregating and displaying cellular internet performance testing results.

- Produced daily aggregate statistics for cellular internet performance testing results using Python.
- Worked with stake holders to gather requirements and ensure the process was able to meet stringent regulations, especially regarding user privacy.
- Designed and published maps using Tilemill.
- Designed data models in Mongo for storing aggregate statistics.
- $\mbox{\sc Performed}$ geospacial queries in Mongo for bucketing results.

Certifications

AWS Solutions Architect Associate

March 2022

Issued by Amazon

Education

Link

University of Maryland

Bachelors

Computer Engineering

Skills

Backend Development Mid			Database Design Mid			Cloud Mid			
JavaScript	NodeJS	Python	MongoDB	Dynamo	PostgreSQL	AWS	Lambda	EC2	S3

Volunteer

DSA National Tech Committee

December 2022 - Present

Volunteer

https://tech.dsausa.org/

I joined the DSA NTC where I have been helping with the development of myDSA, a centralized authentication and registration solution which uses KeyCloak as an identity provider and allows users to update their registration and profile information as well as log in to various other DSA services from a single location.

For my main project, I designed and built a solution for SSO onboarding for other DSA development teams using Github Issues forms along with Github Actions to create, maintain, and execute Terraform code which can register user applications within Keycloak. I"ve also assisted development teams with the overall onboarding process, helping with the initial form, reviewing their form submissions, and helping integrate their app with SSO once they"ve been registered with Keycloak.

Projects

EasyVocab

July 2022 - August 2022

https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/203110167

EasyVocab is an Anki plugin I wrote to enable easy and automatic generation of flashcards for foreign language vocabulary study.

Users can input a list of words they would like to study and EasyVocab will use Google Translate to automatically generate beautiful flash cards. Google TTS is also utilized to create audio pronunciation for each word, and reverse cards which have English on the front and the user"s target language on the back can also be created to help develop a two way association the words in both languages.